import { QuestionsType } from "../utils/types/pages"

export const choice: QuestionsType[] = [
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "electrolytes",
    question: "solvent for all processes in the body",
    answer: "water",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "electrolytes",
    question:
      "maintains concentration of electrolytes within cells and in plasma",
    answer: "ion_transport_mechanisms",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "electrolytes_two_mechanisms",
    question:
      "transport mechanism that requires energy to move ion across cellular membranes",
    answer: "active_transport",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "electrolytes_two_mechanisms",
    question: "movement of ions across membrane based on size and charge",
    answer: "diffusion",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "electrolytes",
    question: "Concentration of solutes per kilogram of solvent (mOsm/Kg)",
    answer: "osmolality",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "other factors affecting blood volume",
    question: "promotes Na+ excretion (H2O excretion)",
    answer: "atrial_natriuretic_peptide_&_b-type_natriuretic_peptide",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "other factors affecting blood volume",
    question: "vasodilation",
    answer: "atrial_natriuretic_peptide_&_b-type_natriuretic_peptide",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "other factors affecting blood volume",
    question:
      "stimulates vasopressin secretion (retains H2O) â€“ independent of Osmolality",
    answer: "blood_volume_receptors",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "electrolytes",
    question: "major extracellular cation",
    answer: "sodium",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "electrolytes",
    question: "major contributor to osmolality",
    answer: "sodium",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "electrolytes",
    question: "principal extracellular osmotic particle",
    answer: "sodium",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "sodium",
    question: "active transport",
    answer: "Na+/K+-ATPase_ion_pump",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "sodium",
    question: "prevents osmotic rupture of cells",
    answer: "Na+/K+-ATPase_ion_pump",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "sodium",
    question:
      "affect Na+ excretion through aldosterone, angiotensin II, and ANP",
    answer: "blood_volume_status",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "sodium",
    question:
      "blocks aldosterone and renin secretion, and inhibits action of angiotensin II and vasopressin",
    answer: "atrial_natriuretic_peptide",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "sodium",
    question: "decreased plasma sodium concentration (<135 mmol/L)",
    answer: "HYPONATREMIA",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "sodium",
    question: "increased plasma sodium concentration (>145 mmol/L)",
    answer: "HYPERNATREMIA",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    referRefName: true,
    refName: "hypernatremia causes a",
    question: "a candidate in excess water loss except",
    answer: "bruises",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    referRefName: true,
    refName: "hyponatremia causes a",
    question: "a candidate in increased Na2+ loss",
    answer: "diabetes",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    referRefName: true,
    refName: "hyponatremia causes b",
    question: "a candidate in increased water retention",
    answer: "ketonuria",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    referRefName: true,
    refName: "hyponatremia causes c",
    question: "a candidate in water imbalance",
    answer: "hepatic cirrhosis",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "electrolytes",
    question: "The major intracellular cation (105 mmol/L in RBC)",
    answer: "potassium",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "electrolytes",
    question: "The single most important analyte in terms of abnormality",
    answer: "potassium",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    referRefName: true,
    refName: "potassium",
    question: "everything is a function of potassium except",
    answer: "DNA replication and mRNA translation",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "electrolytes",
    question: "most abundant cation in the body",
    answer: "calcium",
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    refName: "electrolytes",
    question: "excreted in urine and sweat",
    answer: "chloride",
  },
]

export const otherAnswers = [
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    lessonName: "electrolytes",
    refName: "hypernatremia causes a",
    values: [
      "Diabetes insipidus",
      "Renal tubular disorder",
      "Profuse sweating",
      "Hyperventilation",
      "Diarrhea",
      "Severe burns",
      "Vomiting",
      "Fever",
    ],
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    lessonName: "electrolytes",
    refName: "hyponatremia causes a",
    values: [
      "Hypoadrenalism",
      "Potassium deficiency ",
      "Diuretic (Thiazides)",
      "Ketonuria",
      "Salt-losing nephropathy",
      "Prolonged vomiting or diarrhea",
      "Severe burn",
    ],
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    lessonName: "electrolytes",
    refName: "hyponatremia causes b",
    values: [
      "Renal Failure",
      "Nephrotic syndrome",
      "Hepatic cirrhosis",
      "Congestive Heart Failure",
    ],
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    lessonName: "electrolytes",
    refName: "hyponatremia causes c",
    values: [
      "Polydipsia",
      "Syndrome of Inappropriate ADH secretion (SIADH)",
      "Pseudohyponatremia",
    ],
  },
  {
    refID: "M2-L1",
    lessonName: "electrolytes",
    refName: "potassium",
    values: [
      "Skeletal and Cardiac Muscle Contraction",
      "Neuromuscular excitability",
      "ICF volume regulation",
      "Hydrogen Ion Concentration",
    ],
  },
]
